In this assignment we will create a new project,
在这个任务中,我们会建立一个新项目
import our assets, save our main scene
导入资源,保存主场景
and set up the basic foundations for our game.
做一些游戏中的基础设定.
Let's begin by creating a brand new project.
我们先从建立一个全新的项目开始.
We can do this by selecting File - New Project.
单击File -> New Project.
This opens the Project Wizard.
项目指引会被打开.
In the Project Wizard we can open an existing
在项目指引中,我们可以打开一个已有的项目
project or create a new one.
或者建立一个新的项目.
We will be creating a new project.
现在我们建立一个新项目
First we need to set a location for our new project.
首先,我们要设定新项目的存放位置
We can do this by selecting the Set button,
单击Set按钮选择
which brings up a Save As dialogue box.
会出现另存为对话框
I'm going to put this new project on my desktop.
这里将新项目放在我的桌面
I will call it Space Shooter.
命名为太空射击
Save this and return to the wizard.
保存然后回到项目指引界面
Now if we look at the desktop
如果现在查看桌面
we will see that no files have been created.
我们并不会看到新建的文件
We have simply set the path to the location
我们只是设置了
where Unity will build the new project.
Unity建新项目的路径
At this stage we have the choice to import
下一步是选择
packages of assets we have on our computer
我们电脑上将要要导入的资源包
These could be packages that came from the
这些资源包可能来自于
original install, packages from the asset store
原始安装,asset store(资源商城)
or packages that we have saved ourselves.
或者我们自己保存的资源.
For this assignment we want a new clean
目前这个任务需要一个
empty project, so we won't select
全新的空的项目,所以我们
any packages to import.
选择不导入任何资源包.
Click on Create Project to create this new project.
单击Create Project来建立这个新项目
Unity will close the existing project,
Unity会关闭当前项目,
build the project files and open the new
建立项目文件然后
project in the Editor.
在编辑器中将其打开.
Now we are ready to go.
现在我们准备好了.
The next step is to import the
下一步
assets for this project.
导入项目所需资源
Most likely you will download these from the
最便捷的方式是从Unity教学网站和asset store
learn site and asset store.
和asset store(资源商城)下载
When your import is ready
资源导入完毕后
you will see a window like this one.
你将看到这样的窗口.
These are all the files we need for this project.
这些是我们这个项目需要的文件.
Make sure they are all selected.
确保所有文件都被选中.
If not click the All button in the bottom left,
如果有文件没被选中,单击底部左侧的All按钮,
then select Import to import these assets.
然后选择Import按钮导入资源.
Unity will copy these files to our new project
Unity 会将这些文件都拷贝到我们的项目中
compile any scripts and import all of the assets.
编译全部脚本倒入所有的素材资源
We will be creating this project from scratch
我们将使用已有的资源
using the assets provided.
从头创建这个项目
If however you are confused by any step
如果某步骤不清楚
this project does include a Done folder
本项目还包含了一个Done文件夹
which contains the entire project in finished form.
里面包含了已经完成的整个项目.
There is a final scene, Done_Main,
包含最终场景,Done_Main
final scripts, final prefabs and more.
最终的脚本,最终的预制件和其他
Now that we have our assets let's save
现在我们已经有资源了,
the scene that we will be working in.
先保存下工作场景
When working in Unity we will always
Unity的工作界面总有个
have a scene open.
打开的场景
Unity opened a default scene for us
在项目开始的时候
when we started the project.
Unity 会打开一个默认的场景
Our current scene is unsaved.
我们现在的场景还没保存过
We get a hint to remind us if our scene
标题栏会提示我们
has been saved if we read the header bar.
目前的场景是否被保存了
The header bar always lists the scene,
标题栏总是显示场景
project name and build target.
项目名称和编译目标
Our header bar shows Untitled
我们的标题栏显示的未命名
which is our unsaved scene.
就是我们当前这个没保存的场景
Space Shooter, our current project
太空射击,我们目前的项目
and PC, Mac and Linux Standalone
编译目标
which is our build target.
PC, Mac and Linux独立程序
We will discuss build targets in a moment.
我们过一会讲解下编译目标
To save our scene select File - Save Scene,
保存我们的场景,选择File -> Save Scene
or use the hot-key combination.
或者使用热键组合
Scenes need to be saved in our Assets directory.
我们把场景保存在Assets目录下
They can be in any directory within the Assets directory.
的任何一个子目录
I'm going to create a new directory to hold
我这里将新建一个目录来保存场景
my scene, I will call this new directory
新目录命名为
_Scenes.
The underscore is not necessary but I like it
下划线不是必须的，但是我喜欢这么做
as it will sort this directory to the top of
因为它会把文件夹排在
my project view where it will be easy to find.
项目视图的最顶端，这样容易找到它
Next I will name this scene Main
下一步,命名这个场景Main(主要的)
and hit Save to save it.
点击Save键保存.
We can see that we now have a directory called
我们可以看到现在有了个目录
_Scenes and a scene file called Main.
名叫_Scenes和一个场景名叫Main
We can also see Main as the
标题栏也已经变成了
scene listed in the header bar.
场景Main
Now that we have imported our assets and
我们已经导入了资源
saved our scene we need to set our build target.
保存了场景,现在我们要设置编译目标
Whenever we are working on a project we are
当我们做一个项目的时候
always working with a build target.
我们总有一个编译目标
Our current build target is the default
我们目前的编译目标是默认的
PC, Mac and Linux Standalone.
PC, Mac and Linux 独立程序
All of our assets will be imported for this target
我们所有的资源将被导入到这个目标
and all of our scripts will be compiled
我们所有的脚本将会被编译
for this target, so it's important to have our
所以为计划的目标平台
build settings set to the intended target platform.
设定好相关的设置非常重要
Don't forget Unity can have one project
Unity 可以一个项目
and one codebase for all of our build targets
和一个代码库来完成所有的编译目标
and most of what we develop will work
我们开发的绝大多数程序
for all platforms, but we will be developing
所有平台都适用,但是开发中
for only one platform at a time.
每次只选择一个平台
To set our build target we can select
我们可以这样设定编译目标
File - Build Settings, or use the hot-key combination.
File -> Build Settings 或者使用热键
This will bring up the Build Settings window.
这时Build Settings 窗口会弹出
Here we can set the details of our build
这里我们可以设定详细的编译信息
and select the scenes we want to build in to our game.
选择需要编译到游戏中的场景
We want to change the build target to
我们想将编译目标改为Web Player
Web Player, as we will be building and
我们将会将这个项目发布到
deploying this project to the web.
网页上
Click on Web Player to select the web player build target.
选择Web Player选项后网页播放器将作为构建目标
The blue highlight indicates we have selected the Web Player.
蓝色的突出标记意味着我们已经选定了Web Player
We can see the details on the right change,
我们可以在右侧看到变化的细节
but we have not changed the build target.
但是我们的编译目标并没有改变
Our current build target is indicated by the
我们目前的编译目标由
Unity logo and is shown in the header bar.
Unity的图标标识并且在标题栏也有提示
To change build targets select the
点选你需要的编译目标
platform you want and click Switch Platform.
然后单击Switch Platform来更换你的编译目标
Now the Unity logo is associated with
现在Unity图标已经转移到了
our new build target, and that new build
新的编译目标后面了,
target is listed in the header.
标题栏的编译目标也发生了变化
Now that we have set our build target we need to set
现在编译目标已经设定好了
the build details for our game.
下面我们来设置下编译目标的细节
We can do this from the Build Settings window
这个可以通过Build Settings窗口来设定
by selecting Player Settings.
单击Player Settings按钮
This allows us to inspect and change our player settings.
这让我们可以设置和改变我们的玩家设置
If we want to change our player settings and the
在Build Settings窗口未开启的情况下
build window is not open we can select
我们可以选择
Edit - Project Settings - Player.
Edit -> Project Settings -> Player
With Player Settings open in the Inspector
Player Setting会在编译器窗口中打开
we can change both project-wide settings
这里可以配置项目的通用设定(平台无关)
and platform-specific settings.
或者项目的针对某平台的具体细节
For more information on player settings
更多的关于Player Setting的信息
see the details linked below.
请参考下方的网页连接
For this project we can leave everything at
对当前项目来说所有设定都保持默
default except Resolution.
除了分辨率
I would like this Space Shooter game to have
我希望这个太空射击项目
the feeling of an upright arcade game,
有一种自上而下街机式的感觉
portrait rather than landscape,
纵向而非横向的
so let's change the resolution to 600 by 900.
所以让我们把分辨率设为宽600高900
So that we can see an accurate representation
这样可以更好的展示游戏场景
of our game let's make sure that
同时,我们还可以通过Game view
the aspect ratio in the Game view
中的长宽比来确认我们的分辨率设置
is set to Web.
并且设置是Web
This will use the 600 by 900
将使用宽600高900的分辨率
size and aspect ratio.
和长宽比
With this size and aspect ratio however
但是从左下方的游戏视图看
I do notice that the game view looks cramped
视图又窄又小
and small in it's window.
并不太适合我们编辑
I'm not sure this is how I want to view my game
我并不想使用这样的游戏视图
as I develop.
来做开发
The solution to this is easy, change the layout.
解决方法很简单，改变布局就好了
I'm going to grab the Game view tab and drag
把Game视图选项卡抓起来,
it up to the top between the Scene view and Console.
拖到最上面Scene 视图选项卡和Console选项卡之间
This will give me a big easy to read view
现在视图变得又大又好看了
of my scene, game and console.
同时scene, game, console中的东西也都变大了
Undoubtedly you will have a different layout.
也许你的视窗布局与我的不同
but be aware that changing the layout is easy
但是你已经知道了改变视窗布局很简单
Now that I've changed the layout let's save it.
我已经把我的视窗布局改好了，让我保存一下
If we don't save our layouts and we reselect
如果不保存视窗布局
the current layout our layout will return
当我们再次打开当前的视窗布局时
to the last saved configuration.
视窗布局会恢复到之保存的布局的样子
To save the layout select Layout and choose
保存视窗布局,点击Layout然后选择
Save Layout.
Save Layout(保存视窗布局)
Either save over the current layout to update it
可以覆盖当前的视窗布局文件
or choose a new name for a new layout.
或者给当前视窗布局起个新名字
I'm going to create a new layout and I'm going to
这里我将建一个新的视窗布局
call it Space Shooter.
并且命名它为Space Shooter(太空射击)
Now that I've changed my layout I can return to
假设我改变了现有的视窗布局，
this one by simply selecting it from the
我可以通过点击Layout 的下拉菜单
Layout pull-down menu.
重新选择Space Shooter来恢复布局
That's it for setting up this project.
这就是关于项目设置相关的内容
Now that we've setup the project, in the next
现在我们已经配置好了项目
assignment we will setup the main player game object.
下一个任务设定最主要的玩家对象